<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<seiscomp>
	<module name="scart" category="Utilities" standalone="true">
		<description>
		Import/export MiniSEED data to/from SDS archives.
		</description>
		<command-line>
			<synopsis>
			scart [options] {archive-dir}
			</synopsis>
			<description>
			The last option has to be the archive directory when dump mode is enabled.
			When no archive directory is explicitly given,
			$SEISCOMP_ROOT/var/lib/archive or the current directory
			is used depending on whether $SEISCOMP_ROOT has been set or not.
			The default operation mode is import. That means that a multiplexed
			MiniSEED file or another record source such as ArcLink is used to import
			records into a SDS structure.
		</description>
			<group name="Verbosity">
				<option flag="v" long-flag="verbose">
					<description>
					Verbose mode.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="h" long-flag="help">
					<description>
					Display a help message.
					</description>
				</option>
			</group>
			<group name="Mode">
				<option flag="" long-flag="check">
					<description>
					Check mode. Check all files
					in the given directory for erroneous miniSEED records.
					All sub-directories are included. If no directory is given,
					the default SDS archive is scanned. Checks are only complete
					for files containing exactly one stream. More complete checks
					are made with scmssort.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="d" long-flag="dump">
					<description>
					Set export (dump) mode. Records are retrieved from an archive and
					written to standard output.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="I">
					<description>
					Import mode (default): Specify the recordstream URL to read
					the data from for archiving. When using any other
					recordstream than file, a stream list file is needed.
					Specifying - implies file://- (stdin). If no mode is
					explicitly specified, -I file://- is assumed.
					</description>
				</option>
			</group>

			<group name="Processing">
				<option flag="c" argument="channels">
					<description>
					Channel filter to be applied to the data streams.
					Default for Dump: "(B|E|H|M|S)(D|H|L|N)(E|F|N|Z|1|2|3)"
					Default for Import: "*"
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="E">
					<description>
					Dump mode: sort records according to their end time.
					Default: start time.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option long-flag="files" argument="count">
					<description>
					Dump mode: Specify the number of file handles to cache.
					Default: 100.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="i">
					<description>
					Ignore records without data samples.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="l" long-flag="list" argument="file">
					<description>
					Import, dump mode: Use a stream list file with time windows instead
					of defined networks and channels (-n, -c and -t are ignored).
					The list can be generated from events by scevtstreams. One
					line per stream. Line format: starttime;endtime;streamID
					The time format is the same as described in option '-t'.

					Example:

					2019-07-17 02:00:00;2019-07-17 02:10:00;GR.CLL..BH?
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="m" long-flag="modify">
					<description>
					Dump mode: Modify the record time for real time playback.
					The first record time is NOW. The relative time of
					successive records to the first one are kept.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="n" argument="networks">
					<description>
					Import, dump mode: Data stream selection as a comma separated list 
					"stream1,stream2,streamX" where each stream can be NET or NET.STA
					or NET.STA.LOC or NET.STA.LOC.CHA.
					If CHA is omitted, it defaults to the value of -c option. 
					Default: "*"
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="" long-flag="nslc" argument="file">
					<description>
					Import, dump mode: Stream list file to be used instead of
					defined networks and channels (-n and -c are ignored)
					for filtering the data by the given streams. Dump mode:
					Use in combination with -t! One line per stream, line
					format: NET.STA.LOC.CHA

					Example:

					GR.CLL..BH?
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="" long-flag="rename" argument="rule">
					<description>
					Import, dump mode: Rename stream data according to the provided
					rule(s). A rule is "[match-stream:]rename-stream" and match-stream
					is optional. match-stream and rename-stream are in the
					"NET.STA.LOC.CHA" format. match-stream supports special
					charactes "?" "*" "|" "(" ")". rename-stream supports the
					special character "-" that can be used in place of NET, STA,
					LOC, CHA codes with the meaning of not renaming those.
					"-" can also be used as the last character in CHA code.
					Multiple rules can be provided as a comma separated list
					or by providing multiple --rename options.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="s" long-flag="sort">
					<description>
					Dump mode: Sort records by [start-]time. To sort records by their
					endtime use -E.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option long-flag="speed">
					<description>
					Dump mode: Specify the speed to dump the records. A value of 0 means
					no delay otherwise speed is a multiplier of the real time difference
					between the records. When feeding the records directly into the replay
					pipe a value of 1 (real time) is recommended.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="t" argument="timeWindow">
					<description>
					Import, dump mode: Specify the time window (as one properly
					quoted string) to dump records for. Times are UTC and
					separated by a tilde &quot;~&quot;. To dump one hour of
					waveform data between 2008/01/01 00:00:00 and 2008/01/01
					01:00:00 use
					&lt;-t &quot;2008-01-01 00:00:00~2008-01-01 01:00:00&quot;&gt;.
					</description>
				</option>
			</group>

			<group name="Output">
				<option flag="o" long-flag="output">
					<description>
					Dump, Import mode: Write data to given file instead of creating
					a SDS archive. Deactivates --stdout. Deactivated by --test.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option long-flag="print-streams">
					<description>
					Print stream information only and exit. Works in import, dump
					and check mode. Output: NET.STA.LOC.CHA StartTime EndTime.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option long-flag="stdout">
					<description>
					Import mode: Write to stdout instead of creating a SDS archive.
					Deactivated by --test and --output.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option long-flag="test">
					<description>
					Test input only, deactivate all miniSEED output. This switch is
					useful for debugging and printing stream information with
					--print-streams.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="" long-flag="with-filecheck">
					<description>
					Import mode: Check all accessed files. Unsorted or unreadable
					files are reported to stderr. Checks are only complete
					for files containing exactly one stream. More complete
					checks are made with scmssort.
					</description>
				</option>
				<option flag="" long-flag="with-filename">
					<description>
					Import mode: Print all accessed files to stderr after import.
					</description>
				</option>
			</group>
		</command-line>
	</module>
</seiscomp>
